hi welcome back to the wheel of life
retreat online retreat kind of cool
right and I'm very pleased to have Joe
shopping Allyson helping me to translate
thank you for coming
and again thank you and Allison for
thank you and Stanley for helping me for
so many years yeah
so we're on this is going to be online
session number two segment tooth
and today we're gonna do a meditation
together
there's a special way to prepare for
meditation
in Tibetan is called Yin logged in
and these are seven different steps to
prepare properly for a meditation
and I know a lot of you have heard them
before
and of course I've been teaching them
for 10 years during these normal
teachings
but my hope is that and by the way I'd
like to thank the ACI executive director
Tim Lowen out
and I'm very grateful that he's really
organized this online retreat
among all the other things he does
and I was kind of excited to do the
retreat because I think many more people
will be able to enjoy that they don't
have to travel somewhere and spend a lot
of money
so I feel like a lot of people who
haven't been able to come to the alarm
room retreats in the last 10 years will
be able to attend this one
and so I think it's good for all of us
if we can just review these
preliminaries to a meditation
and so I apologize if you heard these
seven steps before
but I think they're extremely important
and I myself do them almost every day
I like to say that you know you can't
run a race in the Olympics
if you don't warm up first
and I think it's easier to warm up your
body than it is to warm up your mind
when I was young and I was first
learning to drive a car
which Alison promised to learn this year
I remember the teacher told us first
thing the teacher told us
when you get in your car
start the car
and then wait for three or four or five
minutes
don't drive it right away
because card needs time to warm up
and he said that your car will last
twice as long if you warm it up
and you know the last used car I had
when I lived here
it was almost 30 years old
and it lasted fine for 30 years
in fact it's still running I gave it to
my friend
so that's a big piece of knowledge for
everyone
warm up your car
just for five minutes
there's a there's a heat hot and cold
needle in your car it goes like this
so wait until the needle goes off of
cold
and meditation is the same
so I've been meditating for I don't know
over 40 years
and I still cannot start a meditation
cold
even after 40 over 40 years of
meditating I need to warm up my
meditation line before I start
meditating
and that warm-up has become a very
enjoyable and precious part of my life
so I actually in the morning I'm I look
forward to having coffee and meditation
warm up
so we're gonna do that warm-up together
and then I'm going to teach you to other
kinds of meditation sort of warmups
and in my opinion
all of your meditations you could every
day you could choose one of these three
warm-ups to put in your meditation
the first warm-up which is called the
seven part warmup
it's a focus is one of the teachers in
your life
and the theory behind that warmup
is called suction suction
so suck means just before you do your
main meditation
try to collect some real quick good
karma
and John means just before you start
your main meditation
try to clean some bad seeds out of your
mind
and I don't know right now it's a spring
in Arizona when I'm talking
this is the actual week that we are
planting most of our garden
first we do the job
we get rid of all the old dirty leaves
and old problems in the soil we clean
the soil
when you're preparing for meditation
it's very very sweet to clean any bad
seeds you made in the last 24 hours
so don't try to think of all the bad
things you did in your life you will
never start your meditation
it's very powerful and it's enough to
just think about the main bad seed you
might have planted in the last 24 hours
then you do the sock part suck means
make some instant good karma
so John is like cleaning out the soil
making its clean for the new plant
and in sauk is kind of like put
fertilizer and some water on the plate
and the plan is your meditation
now the easiest way to clean away your
bad seeds the easiest way to plant some
new good seeds
is to invite one of the teachers in your
life to meditate with you
so these seven steps for preparing for
meditation
they're all based on one of your
teachers
later in this series of 25 videos
I'll teach you a special way to prepare
for your meditation
which is more based on schemata
and shemitah means making your mind very
very peaceful so you can see emptiness
so sometimes we'll do this seven steps
focused on art one of our teachers
but sometimes the preparation for a
meditation this month
we'll be a traditional preparation for
summit amenities
which is making the mind quiet enough to
see emptiness
and then we'll have a third kind of
meditation warmup
and that will be based on emptiness
itself
so three kinds of warm-up
and today we're going to do this 7 step
warm-up together
and it's based on our teacher
we'll be choosing one of the teachers in
our life
of course the most powerful example
would be your heart teacher if you have
a hard teacher
the short definition of a heart teacher
it's the teacher who help you the most
in this life
so you can use that would be the most
common example of teacher to use for
this manatee
but you could use other teachers in your
life
your dad and your mom were your first
grade teachers
and then obviously in your school life
you met everyone met a few special
teachers in their life
sometimes it's not a school teacher
sometimes it's a sport teacher or an art
teacher or a music teacher
later on you met someone who taught you
how to do your occupation your job
that's a special teacher in our land
if you're married then your wife or
husband is a great teacher in your life
if you have children those are great
teachers
even in your middle age your your
parents who are elderly are nice
teachers to have in your name
you can if you don't have a hard teacher
you could also just imagine
and you could bring that teacher to
prepare for these seven steps of
meditation
and of course you could take your
historical teachers
could be Buddha Jesus Muhammad Moses
Confucius Lao Tzu many many choices
now just in the last few weeks
my personal favorite has been nagashi in
the iana gardener
so I've been doing the seven steps with
him
and then every I don't know every three
weeks or so you can change the teacher
or every day if you want
so the picture we used to introduce this
segment
it shows a monk walking down a country
road
and I've I've visited many times the
place where the gardener is supposed to
have been born in and studied
in Tibetan it's called better you
kind of like the land of the coconuts
so I always imagined when I when I think
I'm the guys
I don't like to close my eyes and think
about a painting
or a statue
I like to think of the gardener walking
down a road to his house
and he's just like a real person
it's somehow I imagine he's very kind of
funny person
and extremely
and extremely morale and a great
understanding emptinesses and why he
sometimes he's called the aria
so let's start our seven steps
if you don't know how to prepare your
meditation space
or the correct
to
I taught it in the first two years of
the ten years
and I suggest you go check it on the
knowledge base
and I'll ask Tim to put the link up for
you
at the end of this video
okay so let's get ready to meditate
the main thing is to be comfortable
the most comfortable place in my house
is my couch
and I meditate on the country
and it's just very comfortable to me
so sit somewhere where you don't have to
move
and sit up straight
it's always good to put some cushions to
raise the back of your pickle bottom
your hands are comfortable on your legs
anyway that's comfortable for you
sometimes I will put a small cushion in
my lap
and I'd like to rest my hands there
most important is your back is straight
small smile on your face
don't you know crunch up your face don't
wrinkle don't frown
okay here we go
the mouth should not be too tired
the lips should be relaxed
the forehead should be relaxed
the eyelid should be nice
the hands should be relaxed
the back is straight
the shoulder blades are priests together
and your chest comes out a little bit
which means that your hands might come
back
more on your thighs than on your knees
it's very good for your posture
if your lower abdomen
is firm
but not you know pulled in with effort
so how to get that firm abdomen which
gives you a strong back
there's a there's a nice trick
when you breathe out
and you finish your out-breath
then consciously tried to push out a
little more air from your lungs
and that will tighten your lower abdomen
and that will make it easier to sit up
straight
so let's start with ten breaths
before we start the first of the seven
steps
you
very slow exhale
at the end of the exhale press a little
more breath out
don't worry about the in-breath it will
take care of itself
make sure lower abdomen is tightening
slightly as you at the end of the
out-breath
pushing out the last bit of air from
your lungs
it will also prevent a buildup of prana
or no more teeth
and then you won't feel you won't get
feeling some nervousness as you meditate
smile smile
I let yourself
let's do ten long exhales
you
now we'll start the first of the seven
warm-up steps
invite one of those teachers to come to
sit with you
could be any of those teachers we talked
about
very powerful person to stop junk with
them
very powerful for planting good see it's
very powerful for cleaning god sees
you
and you invite them and they come and
sit in front of you
on the same level
I like to say knee to knee
and to understand they are not a statue
or a painting
it's a real person in front of me
I can see their chest moving with their
breath
I can feel the subtle warmth from their
body need to meet
good people have a certain delicate
fragrance to do
like a very subtle Jasmine smell
so get this teachers image in front of
you it's not a painting it's a real
person
your eyes are closed
but their eyes are open
they are looking at you as humidity
and they're very pleased with you that
you are meditating
just enjoy being with them
we're gonna meditate together
you
the second of the seven form up steps
is to make an offering to your teacher
and it just sets the feeling of the
meditation that's very happy
so imagine any beautiful gift
could be I think in the garden and light
coconut
there's a traditional offering to to
imagine the whole sky covered with
flowers
and make this offering
there's a
very special offering
to your teacher
and that is to bow down to that teacher
by thinking about some
the quality that they had
so I'm thinking of IANA gardener
good humor funny person
extremely brilliant
and knows how to write beautiful
beautiful short things
so I just appreciate the gardener
by offering
you appreciate your own teacher
you
the third of the seven preparation steps
is to clean away the bad seats you've
made in the last 24 hours
so spend a few minutes to open your
heart
let your teacher look inside
and show them the mistakes you have made
in the last 24 hours
don't be shy
be completely honest
and that kind of willingness to show
your teacher your mistakes
and to promise them you'll try harder
today
this kills the soul dances
and that will make your meditation much
sweeter
you
firstly I'd like to spend 10 breasts on
each of the seven steps
sometimes 20 if my mind is is kind of
busy
you
okay now preparation step number four
we're gonna
balance thinking about the bats ease
by thinking about some good things we
did
it's very much human nature
to focus on our mistakes
and we don't give equal time to the good
things we did
so now ten relaxed breath
thinking about the sweetest things you
did mostly for other people in the last
24 hours
you can you can include your meditation
time as something you're happy about
okay here we go ten breaths
what are some of the sweet things you
did in the last 24 hours
for other people
you
and now we're ready for the fifth of the
seven preparation steps
and in our mind we asked our teacher to
continue teaching us
remember that the teachers teaching can
come to us in many ways
oh sure sometimes we get a video talking
about the steps to the path
maybe we read a scripture
maybe we go to listen to a teacher in
person
but negative things also teaches a lot
the challenges and disappointments in
our life they often teach us more than
the successes
so here in this fifth step
it can be a kind of surrender
Oh teacher
please teach me
let
good teachings come to me
and let difficult teachings come to me
and I will have courage
I will be strong
and I will also learn from the difficult
parts of my life
so I trust you
send me sweet Dharma teachings
but please also send me difficult
teachings problems in my life
like very challenging viruses
and I will do my best to become a better
person from these challenges
you
then when difficult situations come to
you please remember you asked your
teacher to send them
you
and don't get discouraged and don't get
off balance
use them to become stronger
when difficult times come to you use it
as a reason to serve more people
this virus is an excellent time for
Buddhists
this is a great opportunity to show
other people what is a Buddhist
the more dangerous life is
we had
and fears that people have
a real Buddhist person steps up this is
their time to to show how much they can
help people
you
if a buddhist person has a face mask
that another person does not have a face
mask
the Buddhist person happily gives the
face master to other person
and we're happy we had the chance to do
it
you
a sixth preparation step
is to ask this teacher to stay in her
life
I was tempted not to leave our life
a karma the good seeds to have a teacher
they are perhaps the most rare seeds in
the world
and may I always plant those seeds to
have you in my life
please stand my name
you
a seventh step in a meditation
the last one
it comes after the actual meditation
so you do these six steps that we just
did
then you do your actual meditation which
might be one of the steps of the path
like a death meditation
or an emptyness meditation
or at own land exchanging or sorry
giving and taking meditation
or exchanging myself and others
and then after you finish the meditation
you think about all the good things you
planted by doing the meditation
and then you very consciously put them
in the bank
when you dedicate any good seed to
another person's happiness
and that city's protected and it will
always stay with you
so paradoxically
mmm you keep the seed by giving it away
so the seventh step of meditation
after your main meditation is completed
then imagine that you are sharing the
good seeds you planted by meditating
and you are sending them out to all the
people in this room
start with people who are in the same
room
then share those good seeds with other
people in your neighborhood
then send the seeds to all the people in
your city
and share them with everyone in your
country
then share them with everyone in this
planet
and then send them out to outer space to
share with other people living in other
worlds
there's a tradition to do this sharing
of the good seats of our meditation
by imagining those seeds as a golden
life
and at the end of our meditation
we will take at least three very very
slow deep exhales
and we will send those good seeds out
share them with other people
as a beautiful goal in life
okay let's do it together
you
one last suggestion about your
meditation
and then we're finished with this second
segment and this month's practice
so I've been meditating for over 40
years
but there have been periods in my life
when I got I became busy
maybe I was too busy teaching meditation
and I didn't have time to do my own
melody
and I just want to tell you that this
will happen to every meditator
and then don't get very disturbed
when you're ready
start your own meditations again
after many years of meditating
start with the very short meditations
fifteen minutes
20 minutes start back or begin
meditation with short ones
then once a week
increase those meditations by just one
minute
so this week 15 minutes
every day
same time is helpful
and on Sunday
in Christus 16 minutes
and the next Sunday Sunday increase to
17 minutes
and in this way within half a year
you will have a very good 4050 minutes
of meditation
and within a year you'll have a very
good one hour of meditation
and that's our goal
to have one hour of meditation for days
to build up to one hour
which is perfect for seeing emptiness
slowly open your eyes
take a good stretch
thank you I'll listen for Chauncey
and see you guys in segment three
you